On today's episode, I sat down with Cupid and Hercules of the Groom Lake team.
Groom Lake is a security firm focused on both protecting companies in the crypto space from
exploits and recovering funds when exploits do occur. Today's guests' true identities remain
redacted for security purposes given their field of work, but they were generous enough to join
me for a discussion on cybersecurity and crypto and how today's attackers are looking to carry
crime. In the episode, we discussed the threat posed by nation-state-level threat actors,
what companies should be doing to enhance their own security, and how the security landscape
in crypto stands to evolve. I hope you enjoy our conversation.
But only as an expression of their personal opinion.
This podcast is for informational purposes only.
Cupid and Hercules from Groom Lake appreciate you guys joining us. I want to dive right in.
My understanding of Groom Lake and what people in the industry might be vaguely familiar with
is that it's a private military organization combating cybercrime and crypto specifically.
What does that mean and what happens when you guys are called into action?
So Groom Lake, while we don't own any tanks or things like that, we on top of the retained
approach to security and intelligence that we do, that military aspect really comes in when
you're looking at not just the intelligence work to do some very strategic campaigns to find out
information, but also the incident response aspect because we can deploy to physically go
after hackers as well. So that's where that military aspect really comes to play.
Can you talk about what engagements will look like or how you'll engage with firms in this space?
Typically, firms come and engage with us because they want to have this security
and intelligence attachment to their team so that nothing happens. So we come in and we
layer in security and intelligence over time and we have this close concierge relationship with them.
And what does that look like? What that looks like is where you're layering in
Web 2 security fundamentals. That's where we really focus because that's where
over half of the hacks that occur are happening, especially as the landscape has shifted and
nation states are seeing that they're happening via Web 2 vulnerabilities is what you're saying?
Yeah, I would say her. Do you want to jump in on that?
Most definitely. Specific to a lot of the exploits and issues that we face in crypto,
a lot of people tend to believe that the main focus needs to be on chain,
auditing your code and so forth. But the hard truth is the human element and the misconfiguration
side of the house is truly the weakest link that we see in the industry. A lot of the whales and
these protocols tend to try to build very, very quickly. And in doing so, they actually are very
stressed out and they skip a lot of the fundamental things that they should put in place to prevent
a successful hack of an account. Zoom is a great example, which we'll get into a little bit later,
I assume. But there's a lot of people in the space that are unfortunately being targeted quite
heavily by North Koreans to actually be social engineered by posing as a friend,
which will eventually lead to them getting hacked and then, of course, funds being drained.
Is that a vulnerability in particular that's top of mind for you guys at the moment? Would
you say it's one of the more common ones? I would say so. Right now, there's been a major
shift in the industry, mainly because a lot of the advanced threats like nation state and even
very young people that are just being DJ and hackers are starting to go after crypto just
because it's becoming more popular. So if you look at the adoption curve of crypto as a whole,
I would say it's near one to one of what the threat actors are actually going after as well.
And they are starting to realize that social engineering of people is the biggest link. So
yeah, it's definitely becoming the biggest thing in the space. And with that, we've actually geared
a lot of our security schedule, if you will, with these clients non boring, specific to operational
security. So actually getting them into a room, educating them on these issues in the space and
as well as how to prevent them if they do occur. And I think the other thing to hone in on on this
topic is that you have different people who have different security concerns based off of the business
vertical that they work at a company. So a developer is going to have very different security concerns
than a head of marketing or someone in BD. And these people who want to socially engineer
companies know this and they're going to go after you accordingly. So they'll approach them as maybe
a fake investor that's been a common one, maybe come with job offers for dev, all these different
ways to just get people to click that link, have that conversation, and then they start to exploit
them and pivot through the company. So by understanding the social engineering, these social
exploit attempts, they'll pretend to be some sort of actor that would do business with a firm, for
example, and exploit them via that direction. What are the workflows that you guys will put in place
for partners when they're under this vulnerability? I'll dive into the first part of the question
and then transition to that. But not just investors and stuff that we're seeing in social engineering.
At this point, we've actually seen that a lot of the threat actors will actually do their research
on people who are targeting on individuals, you're saying. Correct. So let's say friends,
family, people they haven't spoken to in years that they might just have a random connection with
on even LinkedIn, for example, that's when we saw not too long ago. And they'll go ahead, duplicate
the telegram and so forth and then actually attack. But in terms of workflow for preventing it,
there's a couple of ways that we do it. So of course, education, in my opinion,
is the number one factor with things actually educate them, show them one to one of what these
attacks look like. So actually bringing up visuals, explaining these things in depth and so forth and
doing it in a repetitive way toward they actually obtain the information. The second half of that
is taking the preventative steps from the organizational side of actually working with them
as a virtual CISO as you will in turning the culture within the organization to where people
are security minded in general. And then unfortunately, if somebody is targeted, we tend to get them to
a point through education to where they actually know the steps to take immediately to reduce the
likelihood of a successful exploit. And if they get to a point where they are unfortunately exploited,
we will go ahead and be activated, we will join within five minutes, and we will work to contain
the threat and then remediate anything that comes from that. And to add on there, it's a balancing
act. It's between advisement and implementation. And so when you're advising things, you're looking
at a company's onboarding and offboarding practices and identifying gaps that you need to
implement new strategies to make it more secure. It could be how they're accessing certain sensitive
systems and then implementing solutions to make sure that's more secure. But I think the other
big thing to this, and it's why we have intelligence as a core offering, is that intelligence really
complements the security aspect. That's where we can really start to dig in on what would a threat actor
be able to find on this executive team or on the entire company to different people in general.
And what data is newly surfacing as well. Because if you can have that knowledge,
you can, one, know what kind of things you could be approached with from a socially engineered
perspective. But two, work to then mitigate that data footprint that you have. I think a good
example is the other day we had found there was a telegram number being leaked. And we had looked
into the source of that leak and then we had made sure that that was taken down. So now people couldn't
come in and socially engineer them on that front as easily.
Understood. And a lot of the workflows that we talked about, you guys touch on this briefly,
are non-crypto specific ways that exploiters are using to attack crypto companies or organizations?
Are they choosing to attack crypto organizations because of the perceived ability to exploit
funds, maybe as opposed to other organizations? Or why does it seem like the crypto industry in
particular is being targeted? I would say specifically in my experience, I came from a very
traditional financial background doing traditional boring security engineering. And a lot of the
threat actor groups that actually go after just traditional institutions, normally there isn't
a magical honeypot of funds that they can just take. Whereas crypto, it differs. In the traditional
world, a lot of the time they will either steal information or deploy something like ransomware.
And then if they steal the information, attempt to sell it. So that's how they gain the funds.
In crypto, it's much easier because you have those gold bars that are locked behind a safe,
you just have to get into the safe. And unfortunately, because the industry is
still relatively new, obviously, it's a very easy space to attack, unfortunately,
just given the nature of how people operate within the industry.
And are most of the threat actors that you're talking about, are they nation-state affiliated?
I would say in the beginning, yes, a mass majority of them, I'd probably sell near 80%.
But at this point, I'm seeing a relation between both the nation-state actors as well as just
traditional normie hackers. And even the youth, recently, we did an investigation on a website
that was cloned and everything. And we actually saw that the person that was stealing these funds
was 17 years of age, which is quite young, obviously. But yeah, we're seeing still,
of course, that the nation-states for obvious reasons, but even the adoption of the youth
in Gen Z today. How are you able to detect the age of the attacker if you're able to share
something like that? Well, I was going to say prior to that, I mean,
in terms of the age of the attacker, that can be tipped off from if it's an insider threat,
or even some of those intelligence threads that you can pull can allow you to identify
exactly who it is. And so that's how you find out. But what we see from an insider perspective is,
yeah, while it is nation-state sometimes, I think I was telling you last time we spoke
quite through the intelligence work have found the Lazarus Group plant working at a company for
two years as a principal debt when the company was in stealth mode. But we've also found lots of
risks where people are hiring folks who have these obscured backgrounds. There isn't a nice thing to
the anonymous nature of crypto that people really value. But sometimes if you have a multi-billion
dollar company, you may want to know a bit more about the people that you're bringing on the team,
because we have seen rogue actors who aren't connected to nation-states even exploit a company,
steal funds, because it was a crime of opportunity. They were given so much trust and so much access
that eventually over time they made that decision. And that's where we then come in and hunt them
down. From your perspective, are countries like the US making adequate efforts to try and combat
these sorts of threat actors? The United States specifically, and even the world as a whole,
I would say no in all honesty. Just given how the industry operates as a whole,
people are very anti-regulation in a lot of ways. I think unfortunately, but fortunately,
it is really up to the protocols in VCs and so forth to actually become security-minded and start
adopting security-minded policies within work. It's always a cat and mouse game with crime.
And regulation is always catching up to the new attack vectors and the things that folks are
being exploited by. So since consulting and working in crypto, I had seen a shift that more
and more teams are becoming security-minded, where the history of the space, it really started
from this perspective of if you have a smart contract audit, you are good. That is the
trust signal for the investors. That's the trust signal for the users and all the stakeholders
that this is a safe protocol to use. But now that we've seen this ever-increasing shift into these
Web 2 fundamentals, the human side of things, that's really woken people up to I need to
start to implement my own security solutions. And then I think we're going to see more and
more regulation come in on top of that, like SAC2 clients and things like that. So the US,
I would say, does have a good signal of trust, but we still come across many, many companies,
large corporations who don't even have 2FA on some iris environments. And so that's why it's
easy to think this won't happen to me because everyone's so focused on building and just shipping
and getting out there. But I think teams have to have this mindset that engaging, whether it's an
outside entity like Groom Lake, or whether it's bringing on someone that will handle that internally,
you're taking things off your plate to give to an important subject, which is security,
so that you can use your time in a higher leveraged way, which is building the thing,
making that the main thing. Makes sense. You mentioned 2FA, which I think a lot of people
are familiar with. Are there any blanket suggestions you guys would have for organizations that want
to tighten operational security and security generally? Oh, yeah, most definitely. I think
the first one is obviously MFA. It should be enabled and actually enforced across the organization,
because it is extremely easy for a threat actor if they have your password to authenticate them to
your account and then issues arise. But on top of that, if you really want to go the full length,
I would recommend UB Keys as a whole. So it kind of looks like a USB, but it is a very, very more
strengthened version of MFA, if you will, for your accounts. I also think companies as a whole
need to at least be doing, let's say, like a quarterly audit across all environments as a whole.
We commonly find that people genuinely don't know who has, let's say, administrator access or
even access to a lot of their systems. So actually putting an operational procedure on even something
as a quarterly basis to actually go into the systems, verify who is in them and who has access
to what can really make the difference. Understood. And then those are great
suggestions from everything that I've heard in the crypto industry thus far.
I think unfortunately, we also touch on individual safety. And I'd say in today's day and age,
I have my real name here, I guess, I think of being in the crypto industries,
there being a slight additional risk when it comes to your individual safety.
How would you suggest people look at their individual safety in light of some of these
threat actors? I would say the first and biggest one is when it comes to individual safety,
obviously you need to operate with a general sense of operational security.
So if you're going out, going to a club, doing whatever, don't post on your public Instagram
that you're sitting here, you have a million dollar watch on and so forth.
But yeah, I think in general, the biggest thing is the operational security side of the house,
trying to not put your name fully out there if you can. But obviously for some people,
it is required. Just try to operate in a more smart way in your day to day operations. But
Kupa definitely left some comments on that as well. We've been thinking deeply about this for a while
because individuals have their own concerns and threat vectors to consider even individuals
within a company. But there's lots of traders who don't operate with a company.
So a simple answer will be that those individuals will be able to in a sense hire Groom Lake as
we go and launch one of these tools that we have coming up. It's a platform that's going to be really
focused on data leak monitoring and operational security and things like that to really lower
the risks here. But I would say that it is certainly a mindset where most of the people that come to
us, you will see that there's this common thread of how they got exploited. And it's typically that
they were tired, they were rushed, they weren't getting through because whenever we talk to them,
80, 90% of the time it's 2020 hindsight. Oh, I think I've known that. And these are people who
take a huge thoughtful approach to their security. And they've taken to X to say, oh, I'm so secure.
I have so many layers to my security and that's great. But we have to recognize that there's
this mental aspect to it as well. And that if you're moving a lot of funds and you're trying to move
quickly or somebody's trying to rush you for some reason, a big example would be these folks who
poses VCs trying to get people in a call and say, oh, you know, we have a group of VCs or we have all
the advisors in here, jump in the call. Oh, sorry, that link didn't work. Use this one.
And they're trying to make it so you're not thinking. So slowing down and really thinking that
it could be me that they're going after this time. That will go so far in someone's personal
protection and security. The pushed sense of urgency seems to be a really recurring theme.
And I've heard people where they'll get five phone calls and two emails immediately about their
Coinbase account being compromised or about the fact that their transaction last week didn't go
through for some reason. And they create this head rush almost of, I don't know what to do now.
Yeah. And crypto is such a collaborative space that it's okay to reach out to a friend, to someone
else who's security minded and say, hey, does this sound right? Or have you heard of this?
That will help be a third sounding board to just help you slow down as well. Because yeah,
at Coinbase one where people were being rushed with, oh, we're seeing your funds being moved.
That was huge. And we dealt with new cases in that regard.
Yeah. And I've heard stories of people who've talked others off a cliff, like you're saying,
where you're like, you're about to do something, but thankfully we're here before.
Do you guys work with individuals in any capacity experience individual fund loss?
So in the fund loss scenario, yes, it's never just companies that come to us when it comes to a
crypto theft. We've even worked with individuals who have some intelligence need or something that
was very personal to them and private that they needed support with and they didn't know where
else to go. So we've worked with people in that regard. And in terms of the proactive stuff,
yeah, we've worked with individuals in Wales, folks like that. I think with the advent of
this platform reaper, that's going to be that opportunity where many individuals can break
down that barrier to entry and get help. And can you speak about reaper while we're on this
subject and what that does more precisely? Maybe relatedly, I'd love to hear how you think software
offerings for proactive defense and crypto will evolve. Oh, interesting. Okay. I'm interested
to hear your take on the second part, Hercules, but let me give a little lowdown on reaper. So
reaper is a tool that we've developed over time through our folks who have been trained on the
intelligence aspect of our work and capabilities. And it's this 24 seven data leak monitoring tool
that allows us to very deeply find all of the threads that exist on an individual. And we can
do that just from getting an email and a phone number. And people are very surprised when these
data points pop up on what exists on them, because it's even coming up with some account that they
made seven years ago that they totally forgot about is out there. And it's leaking some little
nuanced piece of their information, which then allows it to lead to something else. And that gives
people this big bird's eye view of everything that's out there on them. Future versions of this
will allow us to do things like scrubbing this data, it will allow us to do sim swap detection
so that people can know if they're being actively compromised. So we really see reaper as this
ability for individuals in the space to have this mindful approach to their own operational
security, because that's what the space has really been craving in a big way. And on top of that,
from a business perspective, how nice would it be for an executive or CISO to be able to see
the entire data leak footprint of their whole company and be alerted if anything new comes
up on one of their employees? So the second part of your question, though, could you rephrase that?
What do you think cybersecurity software looks like for crypto in a few years time?
Oh, yeah, most definitely, that's what I get quite excited about. So I'll answer this in a Web2
context and transition it over into our world. So in the Web2 space, we have a ridiculous amount of
security tooling that's SaaS based. It's from every single category that you can imagine from
compliance, which is amazing all the way over to pentesting. But specific to Web3 in crypto in
general, I think we're going to see a massive adoption of these Web2 tools, which we already do
in development. But there definitely will be a lot of new tooling that I think talented engineers
will create over the next couple of years that are definitely security focused, but also take
core components of Web2 to introduce them into the industry in security ways. But I personally
think that there is a mindset that a lot of people have specific to SaaS solutions as a whole in
regards to Web2 security is that they are a all in one solution for everything. But the truth is
these solutions supplement your primary efforts. So I think there will be a lot of software that
is adopted across the industry. But I think having somebody like Grimlike, for example,
is able to lead the efforts and software exists to supplement the other avenues.
Makes sense. That's very helpful. Is this cyber crime that you guys are dealing with? Is it
trending up? Is it trending down? Or which way do you see it moving? It's definitely trending up.
But I would say personally, the increase in social engineering attempts is becoming
more and more crazy. And the tactics that are being leveraged are becoming different every day.
Very sophisticated. Very sophisticated, yes. And there's this thing called TTPs, which are
tactics, techniques and procedures. And whenever we investigate a hack, those TTPs will allow us
to do some association of who may have been responsible behind this. And we're seeing the
social engineering specifically is heavily coming through the nation state groups. And they wait
quite a while to actually execute. And they are using some robust tooling to actually complete
this. They're using custom malware, as well as deepfakes, which I had made a post on Twitter
not too long ago about it. Deepfake technology now as a whole is extremely, extremely good.
So I even thought before this meeting throwing your face online and doing a little thing, but
didn't have enough time. But it's quite crazy at this point. To that point, I'd be amiss not to
mention AI as an added attack vector. You hit the nail on the head, I think with deepfakes.
A lot of companies in the space, to my knowledge, also employ audio verification. You'll respond
with your voice, certifying who you are. Something like that to me seems like a mechanism that will
come under threat in coming years. So how can you be a couple of steps ahead of threat vectors
related to deepfakes, AI mechanisms, et cetera? I think the voice one is something that is often
overlooked because you just think the video you go to the face. And even as of a year ago,
the technology get quite good. I even in my experimentation days took a podcast that FDR
did a very long time ago and threw it in and was able to actually recreate his voice very,
very similarly. And just think if it's good on a computer, imagine a cell phone doing a call,
it would be your spot on. But I think as a whole, we're going to get to a point with AI and these
deepfake technologies as a whole that to actually prevent them, you have to employ a little bit
of true identification if you're onboarding somebody, for example, but also doing things as
simple as telling the person with their hands to simply put it over their face. Because the tech
today, it is quite hard to actually map over the fingers and all. But I also think if it's a friend
or a colleague or somebody similar, I always recommend if things get suspicious, hanging up
the phone and the call and contact them through another means that you believe is safe. So that
could be returning a phone call, right? Unless they're sim swapped, because it is true you can only
spoof outbound unless they're sim swapped or reach out to them on signal, reach out to them on telegram,
or if they're in another room or a friend of a friend call that friend and have them speak to
them individually. Yeah, it was a great suggestions. In the wake of all of the concerns that will
collectively face, when should people reach out to you guys, Groom Lake, and how should they
get in contact? Reaching out to Groom Lake from a company perspective, typically we see people
reach out at all phases, but the most common would be when there's some big milestone approaching,
that's about three months out. And that could be TGE, could be Mainnet launch, anything like that,
any major inflection point in a company. For individuals, when you're thinking about something
like Reaper, this is an opportunity to front runs social engineering attempts. So the sooner,
the better, because then you can have, you know, we're talking about the AI and the implications
of that. But from a defensive perspective, having something that is your personal
hunter killer drone that can just take two pieces of information and look for 100 plus different
attack vectors on you is going to be really big. So the sooner you go and implement security,
whether you're an individual or a company, it's always the better, because security is this
act of layering things over time. And the more time you have to layer countermeasures,
the better off you're going to be. Definitely. And I'll reinforce that point as well.
Doing things early from the beginning is great from an organizational perspective,
because you tend to build a cultural idea around security as a whole. And going into an
organization and reviewing their operational security procedures, their current tech stack,
what their configurations look like across the whole, any change you make tends to introduce
a little bit of friction. It's unfortunately how security works, but with our packages and the
way that we tailor things, we tend to get friction. That's very, very minimal. But going into an
organization that has existed for quite a long time, and has been doing things that they might
have thought is right, but it truly is not up to par. It's harder to go backwards,
and it will take more time. But we have ways to do it, and we are more than happy to do it.
Yeah, it makes sense. Harder to rebuild something and spin around for some time already.
Definitely. I heard that he's in Cupid. I appreciate you coming on and having a conversation
with us, and thank you for the work you continue to do in this space.
Yes, thank you, I. Yeah, man, it's been a pleasure. Thanks for having us on.
Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more
about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. To listen to all of our podcast episodes,
please go to onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.